<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Ton (Jake) Tosirikul</title>
    <link>https://j3t.vercel.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Ton (Jake) Tosirikul</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://j3t.vercel.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Production Issue: what I could and couldn’t do as a new Developer 💥</title>
      <link>https://j3t.vercel.app/blogs/first-prod-incident/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://j3t.vercel.app/blogs/first-prod-incident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working at ExxonMobil for about six months now as a new graduate developer. I’m currently the sole developer maintaining our team’s services. For most of that time, things had been running smoothly. There were no incidents, and I felt fairly confident keeping everything stable. That changed when a production issue occurred—one that didn’t directly involve my part of the system, but it still put me in a position where I had to step up. It was a moment that made me realise just how much I didn’t know—and pushed me to grow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finished my Bsc, what next? 👨‍🎓</title>
      <link>https://j3t.vercel.app/blogs/finish-bsc-what-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://j3t.vercel.app/blogs/finish-bsc-what-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m about to finish my bachelor’s degree in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence in the next two months. The past few months have been a rollercoaster—ranging from regretting the value of my degree to considering a complete career shift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is my reflection on that journey and a breakdown of what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;lets-talk-about-my-degree-disappointment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about my degree disappointment.&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#lets-talk-about-my-degree-disappointment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I originally pursued this degree with the hope of becoming a robotics software engineer. Unfortunately, the reality didn’t match my expectations. Many modules suffered from poor instruction, lack of guidance, and an incoherent syllabus. As a result, I didn&amp;rsquo;t gain the solid foundation needed to become a job-ready robotics engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://j3t.vercel.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://j3t.vercel.app/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I graduated from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kmitl.ac.th&#34;&gt;KMITL&lt;/a&gt; in 2022 with a BEng in Robotics and AI, then continued my studies at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gla.ac.uk&#34;&gt;University of Glasgow&lt;/a&gt;, earning a degree MSc in Software Development in 2023. Since 2024, I’ve been working as a software engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://corporate.exxonmobil.com&#34;&gt;ExxonMobil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I discovered my passion for software development during an internship at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scg.com&#34;&gt;SCG&lt;/a&gt;, where I had the chance to work on factory production monitoring system as software developer and collaborate with experienced AI and IoT engineers. That experience sparked my curiosity and motivated me to pursue a master’s degree to deepen my understanding and expand my skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
