<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Ton Tosirikul</title>
    <link>http://localhost:54096/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Ton Tosirikul</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:54096/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My First Production Issue: what I could and couldn’t do as a new Developer 💥</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54096/blogs/first-prod-incident/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54096/blogs/first-prod-incident/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working at ExxonMobil for about six months now as a new graduate developer. I’m currently the sole developer maintaining our team’s services. For most of that time, things had been running smoothly. There were no incidents, and I felt fairly confident keeping everything stable. That changed when a production issue occurred—one that didn’t directly involve my part of the system, but it still put me in a position where I had to step up. It was a moment that made me realise just how much I didn’t know—and pushed me to grow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finished my Bsc, what next? 👨‍🎓</title>
      <link>http://localhost:54096/blogs/finish-bsc-what-next/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:54096/blogs/finish-bsc-what-next/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Introduction&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m about to finish my bachelor’s degree in Robotics and Artificial Intelligence in the next two months. The past few months have been a rollercoaster—ranging from regretting the value of my degree to considering a complete career shift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog is my reflection on that journey and a breakdown of what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;lets-talk-about-my-degree-disappointment&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about my degree disappointment.&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#lets-talk-about-my-degree-disappointment&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I originally pursued this degree with the hope of becoming a robotics software engineer. Unfortunately, the reality didn’t match my expectations. Many modules suffered from poor instruction, lack of guidance, and an incoherent syllabus. As a result, I didn&amp;rsquo;t gain the solid foundation needed to become a job-ready robotics engineer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
